

# **AKIS GAZEPIDIS**

DATA SCIENTIST

# PROFILE

Data Scientist with experience in information extraction techniques used on documents, building ETL pipelines and training of machine learning models. My passion is to accelerate internal company processes with custom made cloud applications wich lead to data-driven decisions.

### CONTACT



+30 6986777430



akisgazepidis@gmail.com



Peristeri, Athens, 12137, Greece



LinkedIn Profile



Personal Portfolio



**Google Certifications Profile** 



**Microsoft Certifications Profile** 

# HARD SKILLS

- Python
- Snowflake
- Azure Devops
- PostgreSQL
- Azure SQL server
- PowerBi
- Git
- Postman
- Docker
- CI/CD
- MongoDB
- Dbt

### EXPERIENCE

### **DATA ENGINEERING CONSULTANT**

#### **D-ONE**

Apr 2023- Present

- Use ETL pipelines to extract, transform, and load data from various sources.
- Build, test and deploy tables into Snowflake database.
- · Query data from Rest APIs and create collections.

**Project:** Database Integration project from Azure SQL server databases to one unified Snowflake database.

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

### <u>Generali</u>

Jan 2022- Apr 2023

- Integrate Bitbucket version control system in development.
- · Consolidate data with the use of APIs.
- Integrate OCR, Machine Vision & Machine Learning fields to automated processes.

### **DATA SCIENTIST**

### <u>Purposeful</u>

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Collect publication patents through Google's BigQuery.
- Analyze texts with Natural Language Process (NLP).
- Conduct topic modeling using Latent Dirichlet Allocation. (LDA)

**Project:** Build a probabilistic model so as to analyze patents texts.

## SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Team Working

## LANGUAGES

Greek - Native

English - ILTES 6.5

### PORTFOLIO

Optimization of Titan's Mill

**Deep Learning - loan prediction** 

Classcentral scraper

**Image Handwritting Recognition** 

NLP - Climate Change IR System

#### JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST

**Big Blue Data Academy** 

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- · Web scraping with Beautiful Soup, Requests & Selenium.
- Consolidate various data sources using Pandas & JSON.
- Data visualization using Plotly, Dash & Power BI.

**Project:** Build a recommendation system for active jobs depending on a CV input.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **WORKSHOPS - CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft - Data Engineer Associate - Ongoing GCP - Generative AI for ML Engineers - Dec 2023

Microsoft - Data Analyst Associate - Aug 2023

**D-ONE** - BigQuery Essentials - Nov 2023

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE**

<u>American College of Greece</u> - <u>Data Science</u> 2022 - 2024

### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

<u>University of Piraeus</u> - <u>Statistics & Insurance</u> 2011 - 2020

### DATA SCIENCE BOOTCAMP 500 HOURS HANDS-ON

Big Blue Data Academy

Sep 2021 – Dec 2021

- Databases (SQL, MongoDB), APIs & Web Scraping
- EDA & Data Cleaning (Pandas, Numpy, Regex)
- Big Data (PySpark) & Cloud Computing (Amazon Web Services)
- Machine Learning (Scikit Learn) & Deep Learning (Keras)
- · Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Dash, PowerBi)

# DATA SCIENCE ACADEMY 100 HOURS HANDS-ON

Regeneration Academy by TITAN - Code. Hub

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021